In this tutorial video, we use the 11th version of Doshi Marvelous Designer.
If you need to learn the 10th version of Marvelous Designer, please watch the previous video.
In order to make it easier to learn, the Doshi Marvelous Designer is used in this tutorial.
You have simulated the T-shirt version you created and wear it on the virtual model.
The next step is to check if the costume fits on the virtual model.
First, let's learn how to change the virtual model posture.
By changing the posture, you can observe more costume details.
Open the virtual model file folder in the Library window.
You can find the file folder where the virtual model we use is located,
called Female VR, and open the POS file folder.
Double-click the posture file to apply.
You can choose any virtual model posture you want to change.
There is no rule.
In the Marvelous Designer, you can change the posture that matches the default virtual model.
As the movement changes, the costume will also change.
You can see the wrinkle effect under different movements.
If it's just the basic style of clothing, such as the T-shirt in the tutorial,
then POS is enough to check if it fits.
First, let's learn how to compare the length of the radius.
Here we use the sleeve and the sleeve dragon as examples.
You can choose to edit the sewing line tool.
Click the sewing line between them.
When selecting the sewing line, it will display the length of the line on both sides
and the gap between them.
When the gap is displayed as blue,
it proves that the length of the sewing line on both sides is not much,
and it will not particularly affect the seam effect.
However, if it is displayed as red,
it means that the gap between the two sides is relatively large,
which may significantly affect the effect.
Now let's take a look at how to check the fit of the costume in the 3D window,
and how to modify the panels in the 2D window according to the cutout.
First of all, for this model, the sleeves may be a little long.
Delete the excess points,
then you can use the edit panel tool to adjust the length of the sleeves.
When moving points or lines,
click the Shift key to help move along the guide lines.
Now there are some left and right at the bottom,
let's modify the points so that the rhythm on both sides is the same.
Now the overall length of the sleeves is not even,
the length on the outside of the arm is a little long,
and the length on the inside is just right.
We need to use the edit point tool
to adjust the middle position of the bottom to the top.
The bottom of the bottom of the costume is also a little uneven.
First choose the edit panel tool
to move the bottom point downwards to increase the length,
then select the edit point tool
to adjust the bottom to the curve,
and the overall transition is smoother.
Do you still remember what we mentioned before?
Try to get as close to the right angle as possible as possible,
so as to make it more natural and smooth.
Considering the movement of the entire bottom,
we also adjust the back of the costume.
The same is true for the right angle.
I like a longer T-shirt,
so here I stretched the costume a little longer.
Now the butt looks a little tight here,
let's widen the bottom.
Press the Shift key to select more points,
then release the Shift key to move them.
In the process of moving,
you can press the Shift key to use the reference line.
In the previous tutorial,
we merged the sleeves into a plate.
Now we are going to use the same method
to deal with the front and back pieces,
because the front and back pieces of the T-shirt
are a whole plate,
and there is no cross-section in the middle.
When the two symmetrical plates are merged,
they will automatically become an entire left and right plate.
Finally, the pocket is a bit too close to the side,
we can use the adjustment panel tool
to select the entire internal shape,
move it closer to the center,
and after finishing the correction,
save the project file.
To see more details,
please click the link in the explanation column.